Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today, Marco, we're trying to make some plans.
我是Catherine，今天Marco，我们打算做些计划。
We're trying to go to a restaurant, correct?
我们想去一家餐厅，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
We want to go to a restaurant tonight, but before we have to call them to make sure that
我们今晚想去一家餐厅，但在此之前，我们得先打电话确认一下
there is a space or room available for us.
那里有没有空位给我们。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to hear a conversation between a person at a restaurant who works there and
所以我们将听到一段对话，一方是餐厅的工作人员，
a person who would like to go to that restaurant.
另一方是想去那家餐厅的人。
Let's take a listen.
我们来听一下。
Bruno Bistro, how may I help you?
布鲁诺小馆，有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, hello.
是的，你好。
I would like to make a reservation, please.
我想预订一下座位。
Certainly, sir.
好的，先生。
For which day and time, please?
请问是哪天和什么时间？
Tonight at seven.
今晚七点。
I'm sorry, sir, but we are fully booked tonight until eight.
抱歉，先生，我们今晚八点前都订满了。
In that case, eight o'clock is fine.
那样的话，八点也行。
Very well.
好的。
And how many people will attend tonight?
请问今晚有几位用餐？
Four people.
四位。
Lastly, may I please know what name I should make the reservation under?
最后，请问以什么名字预订呢？
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So let's take a look at Language Takeaway.
现在我们来看看“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So first up, Marco, we didn't hear the word restaurant in today's dialogue.
首先，Marco，今天的对话里我们没有听到“餐厅”这个词。
We heard a different noun.
我们听到了一个不同的名词。
We heard this bistro.
我们听到了“小馆”这个词。
That's right.
没错。
The name of the restaurant is actually Bruno Bistro.
这家餐厅的名字其实是布鲁诺小馆。
So this restaurant, the type of restaurant this is, it's actually a bistro.
所以这家餐厅的类型，实际上就是一家小馆。
That's right.
没错。
It's a name like Marco or Catherine, but a bistro is actually a special kind of small
它就像Marco或Catherine这样的名字，但小馆实际上是一种特殊的小型
restaurant.
餐厅。
And I believe it comes from France, right?
而且我觉得它源自法国，对吧？
Right.
对。
That's right.
没错。
So it's kind of small and intimate, maybe some candles and lots of wine, but it's not
所以它比较小巧、温馨，可能有点蜡烛和很多酒，但不像
like a big restaurant.
大餐厅那样。
It's very romantic.
很浪漫。
Right, right.
对，对。
Which usually, I found it means that it's more expensive for some reason.
通常我发现，不知为何它会更贵。
Because it's a bistro, it's automatically more expensive.
因为是家小馆，所以自动就更贵了。
I think maybe in America it's more expensive.
我想在美国可能更贵。
Who knows?
谁知道呢？
Maybe in France it's the cheap option.
也许在法国它是便宜的选择。
That's right.
没错。
Bistro is the kind of place we're at and we'd like to go, so it's probably a popular place.
小馆是我们想去的那种地方，所以它可能很受欢迎。
We need to make a reservation.
我们需要预订。
That's right.
没错。
So as you see there, we have a verb there, to make.
所以你看，这里有个动词“做”。
We want to make a reservation.
我们想“做预订”。
So let's take a look at the noun, a reservation.
那我们来看看这个名词“预订”。
Reservation.
预订。
So this word means to ask the restaurant to hold your seats.
所以这个词的意思是请餐厅为你保留座位。
So you say, listen, I would like to come to your restaurant tonight.
所以你说，听着，我今晚想去你的餐厅。
I don't want to wait when I come, so I will call in advance.
我不想去了再等，所以我会提前打电话。
I'll call early and ask them to save a table for us.
我会早点打电话，请他们为我们留一张桌子。
That's right.
没错。
So this is called making a reservation.
所以这就叫“做预订”。
So it goes together.
所以它们是搭配使用的。
You call to make a reservation or you want to make a reservation.
你打电话“做预订”，或者你想“做预订”。
That's right.
没错。
So the verb is to make.
所以动词是“做”。
So I could say, for example, hey Marco, can you please make a reservation for dinner tonight?
比如，我可以说，嘿Marco，你能为今晚的晚餐做个预订吗？
I'm afraid there might not be any tables left if we wait.
我担心如果我们等的话，可能就没位子了。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
Now, we can use the verb reserve as well, right?
现在，我们也可以用动词“预订”，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So reservation is a noun.
所以“预订”是名词。
To reserve is a verb.
“预订”是动词。
So I can say, hey Marco, can you please reserve a table for dinner tonight?
所以我可以这么说，嘿Marco，你能为今晚的晚餐预订一张桌子吗？
Okay.
好的。
So we can say to make a reservation or reserve a table.
所以我们可以说“做预订”或“预订桌子”。
But you have to say reserve a table.
但你必须说“预订桌子”。
You can't say, I would like to reserve, please.
你不能只说“我想预订，谢谢”。
No, you have to reserve something.
不，你必须预订某个东西。
So if I'm going to a concert, a music concert, I can say, I'd like to reserve two seats for
所以如果我要去听音乐会，一场音乐会，我可以说，我想预订两个座位
the concert.
给这场音乐会。
But if I'm going to dinner, obviously we sit at a table.
但如果我去吃晚餐，显然我们是坐在桌子旁。
So I'm going to reserve a table.
所以我要预订一张桌子。
All right.
好的。
Now, moving on to another verb, the waiter or the person in charge there asked us how
现在，转到另一个动词，服务员或负责人问我们
many people will attend dinner tonight.
今晚会有多少人参加晚餐。
So how many people will attend?
那么有多少人会参加？
To attend.
参加。
Okay.
好的。
This is another verb.
这是另一个动词。
To attend means to be there or to come.
参加的意思是到场或来。
That's right.
没错。
So it's actually a nicer way of saying to come.
所以这实际上是“来”的一种更礼貌的说法。
Instead of him saying, how many people will come tonight?
而不是他说，今晚会有多少人过来？
He says, how many people will attend?
他说，今晚会有多少人参加？
All right.
好的。
So that's a question for the person making the reservation.
所以这是对预订者提出的问题。
How many people total?
总共多少人？
But it's like you say, very polite.
但就像你说的，非常礼貌。
You could say, hey, Marco, how many people do you think will attend your birthday party
你可以说，嘿，Marco，你觉得下周你的生日派对会有多少人参加？
next week?
下周？
That's right.
没错。
So I can say, well, maybe 10 people will attend.
所以我可以回答，嗯，大概10个人会参加。
10 people will attend.
10个人会参加。
So attend, quite a simple verb, but just remember that it means to come or to be present at.
所以“参加”是一个很简单的动词，但只需记住它意味着“来”或“出席”。
All right, great.
好的，很棒。
So let's take a look at our dialogue again, and then we'll be back in a bit with Fluency
那么让我们再看一遍我们的对话，然后我们稍后回来进行流利度
Builder.
构建环节。
Bruno Bistro, how may I help you?
布鲁诺小酒馆，请问有什么可以帮您？
Yes, hello.
是的，你好。
I would like to make a reservation, please.
我想预订一下，谢谢。
Certainly, sir.
当然可以，先生。
For which day and time, please?
请问是哪一天和什么时间？
Tonight at 7.
今晚7点。
I'm sorry, sir, but we are fully booked tonight until 8.
抱歉，先生，我们今晚8点前都订满了。
In that case, 8 o'clock is fine.
那样的话，8点也可以。
Very well.
好的。
And how many people will attend tonight?
那么今晚会有多少人参加？
Four people.
四个人。
Lastly, may I please know what name I should make the reservation under?
最后，请问我应该以什么名字来预订？
Mark.
马克。
All right, we've picked out three phrases for you.
好的，我们为您挑选了三个短语。
Let's take a look at those now on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们在流利度构建环节中看看它们。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right, so the first phrase we have on Fluency Builder is actually a phrase you don't
好的，所以流利度构建中的第一个短语实际上是一个你
want to hear when you're trying to make a reservation.
在尝试预订时不想听到的短语。
The person at the restaurant, the bistro, said, I'm sorry, we're fully booked until
餐厅、小酒馆的人说，抱歉，我们8点前都订满了。
8.
8点前。
That's right.
没错。
So a place that is fully booked or maybe a flight that's fully booked means that it's
所以一个地方“fully booked”或者可能一个航班“fully booked”意味着它
completely full.
完全满了。
There are no available seats or available spots or anything.
没有可用的座位或位置之类的。
All the tables have been reserved.
所有的桌子都被预订了。
All right, so this means that we have to change either the day or the time.
好的，所以这意味着我们必须改变日期或时间。
That's right.
没错。
It's fully booked.
它订满了。
But the nice thing is that after 8 o'clock is not fully booked.
但好的是8点之后没有订满。
There are free tables after 8.
8点之后有空桌子。
That's right.
没错。
And I actually went on to say an interesting phrase to start that sentence.
而且我实际上接着说了一个有趣的短语来开始那句话。
He said, in that case, 8 o'clock is fine.
他说，那样的话，8点也可以。
In that case.
那样的话。
So in that case is a great phrase to use when you're having a conversation with someone
所以“那样的话”是一个很好的短语，当你和别人交谈
or a negotiation, because it's something that we say when the situation, okay, like reserving
或谈判时使用，因为当情况，比如预订桌子，不是我们期望的那样时，我们会说这个。
a table is not exactly the way we hoped it would be.
不是我们期望的那样。
So with today's dialogue, we wanted to book a table at 7 o'clock.
所以在今天的对话中，我们想预订7点的桌子。
There was no table.
没有桌子。
So in that case, in that situation, because it changed from what we thought, we had to
所以那样的话，在那种情况下，因为它和我们想的不一样，我们不得不
book a table at 8 instead.
改订8点的桌子。
That's right.
没错。
So it's usually a response to information that was given to you.
所以它通常是对你收到的信息的回应。
So they say, oh, I'm sorry, there are no tickets available for the zoo today, only for tomorrow.
所以他们说，哦，抱歉，今天动物园没有票了，只有明天的。
In that case, why don't we go tomorrow?
那样的话，我们为什么不去明天呢？
That's right.
没错。
So I wanted to go today, but the situation changed or there's a problem.
所以我想今天去，但情况变了或者有问题。
In that case, let's change our plans.
那样的话，我们改变计划吧。
That's right.
没错。
And lastly, the waiter asked, may I please know what name I should make the reservation
最后，服务员问，请问我应该以什么名字来预订？
under?
以什么名字？
What name I should make the reservation under?
我应该以什么名字预订？
All right.
好的。
Now to make a reservation, we already learned this phrase.
现在说到预订，我们已经学过这个短语了。
It means to reserve a table.
它的意思是预订一张桌子。
Now to make a reservation under a person's name, this is quite different, right?
现在说到以某人的名字预订，这有点不同，对吧？
This means that we're going to save a table, reserve a table, but we have to provide a
这意味着我们要预留一张桌子、预订一张桌子，但我们必须提供一个
name.
名字。
So if we say, okay, one table reserved for four, we don't know who.
所以如果我们说，好的，预留一张四人桌，我们不知道是谁。
So this is the name that you will give the waiter when you arrive at the restaurant.
所以这就是你到餐厅时给服务员的名字。
That's right.
没错。
So that is your table basically, and that's your reservation.
所以那基本上就是你的桌子，那就是你的预订。
So if you go to the restaurant, you say, hello, I have a reservation under the name of Mark.
所以如果你去餐厅，你说，你好，我以马克的名字预订了。
That's right.
没错。
I have a reservation under the name Mark, or I have a reservation for Mark at eight
我以马克的名字预订了，或者我八点
o'clock.
为马克预订了。
Now when they ask the question, they're going to say, what name should we make the reservation
当他们问这个问题时，他们会说，我们应该以什么名字
under?
预订？
That's because, so just think about it as when they make the reservation, they have
这是因为，所以你可以这样想，当他们做预订时，他们有一
this big book.
本大本子。
They write your name and underneath they write the time.
他们写下你的名字，然后在下面写下时间。
What name should we make the reservation under?
我们应该以什么名字预订？
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So we've taken a look at a lot of vocab and some really good phrases.
所以我们看了很多词汇和一些非常好的短语。
So let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
那么让我们最后听一遍对话。
Bruno Bistro, how may I help you?
布鲁诺小酒馆，请问有什么可以帮您？
Yes, hello.
是的，你好。
I would like to make a reservation, please.
我想预订一下，谢谢。
Certainly, sir.
当然可以，先生。
For which day and time, please?
请问是哪一天和什么时间？
Tonight at seven.
今晚七点。
I'm sorry, sir, but we are fully booked tonight until eight.
对不起，先生，我们今晚八点前都订满了。
In that case, eight o'clock is fine.
那样的话，八点也可以。
Very well.
好的。
And how many people will attend tonight?
那么今晚有几位客人？
Four people.
四位。
Lastly, may I please know what name I should make the reservation under?
最后，请问我应该以什么名字预订？
Mark.
马克。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So making a reservation, now this is fairly easy.
所以说到预订，这相当简单。
This is basically what you're going to experience if you call any restaurant to make a reservation,
这基本上就是如果你打电话给任何餐厅预订时会遇到的情况，
right?
对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And it's really important to know how to respond because I know in other languages, sometimes
知道如何回应真的很重要，因为我知道在其他语言中，有时
you reserve seats instead of tables.
你会预订座位而不是桌子。
And so in English, we reserve or we book a table.
所以在英语中，我们预订或预约一张桌子。
Now sometimes you will call a place and you'll say, well, I'd like to make a reservation
现在有时你打电话给一个地方，你会说，嗯，我想预订，
and they will say, I'm sorry, we don't accept reservations.
他们会说，对不起，我们不接受预订。
Yes, this is actually a very frustrating situation, especially if a restaurant or bistro is very
是的，这实际上是一个非常令人沮丧的情况，尤其是如果餐厅或小酒馆非常
popular.
受欢迎的话。
Right.
对。
Because if they don't accept reservations, we don't make reservations, that means that
因为如果他们不接受预订，我们不接受预订，那就意味着
you have to go to the restaurant and maybe wait in line for a table.
你必须去餐厅，可能还要排队等桌子。
That's right.
没错。
That's called, I think, first come, first served, right?
那叫做，我想，先到先得，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
First come, first serve.
先到先得。
So that means that the first people to arrive at the restaurant are the first people to
所以这意味着第一个到餐厅的人
get a table.
第一个得到桌子。
So it's smart to arrive early.
所以早点到是明智的。
That's right.
没错。
So that's what happens.
所以就是这样。
Now there are certain restaurants where you can't make a reservation or different.
现在有些餐厅你不能预订，或者不同。
We took a look at a bistro.
我们看了一个小酒馆。
There's another one, like for example, very popular in the US, a diner.
还有另一种，比如在美国很流行的，小餐馆。
A diner.
小餐馆。
Now this is not a place you need to make a reservation for.
这不是一个需要预订的地方。
Normally a diner is a very casual place to eat.
通常小餐馆是一个非常随意的用餐场所。
You can go at nine o'clock in the morning for breakfast.
你可以在早上九点去吃早餐。
It's not very fancy at all.
它一点也不高档。
Right.
对。
And it's open, I think, 24 hours usually.
而且它通常是24小时营业的。
Many of them are open 24 hours.
很多都是24小时营业的。
And that's why I say it's not a place you need to worry about a reservation because
这就是为什么我说这不是一个需要担心预订的地方，因为
they're usually popular at certain times, but like seven o'clock for breakfast or, you
它们通常在特定时间很受欢迎，比如早上七点吃早餐，或者
know, 12 o'clock for lunch, but you can usually get a table.
你知道，中午十二点吃午餐，但你通常能找到桌子。
Right.
对。
All right.
好的。
So if you guys have any questions or any other doubts, you can find us at EnglishPod.com
所以如果你们有任何问题或其他疑问，可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
and we'll see everyone there.
我们到时候见大家。
You guys are great!
你们太棒了！